<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fix ERR_NETWORK_CHANGED</title>
      <link>/til/2025-09-01-err-net-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/til/2025-09-01-err-net-changed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fix-err_network_changed&#34;&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;ERR_NETWORK_CHANGED&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty annoying issue that I had been facing for months and that it was harming my daily&#xA;productivity to a point that I was considering completely formatting my computer and starting from&#xA;scratch. The issue was the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Every time that I was using an Electron application or I opened a website in my browser that used&#xA;websocket or a persistent communication to a server led to intermitently getting a&#xA;&lt;code&gt;ERR_NETWORK_CHANGED&lt;/code&gt; error. This triggered a restart in the application or website connection.&#xA;For certain applications this was fine, but whenever I was interacting with an LLM or leveraging a&#xA;coding agent with a persistent connection, getting an &lt;code&gt;ERR_NETWORK_CHANGED&lt;/code&gt; error was a major&#xA;setback as it required restarting all the work that it was doing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I tried everything to debug the problem:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I first checked if this could be related with the power saving mode for the Wifi card of my&#xA;Framework laptop, but it was still happening when connected through Ethernet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I disabled my VPNs and reviewed all my firewalls and network policies&amp;hellip; still nothing!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I decided then to directly run &lt;code&gt;sudo journalctl -f -u NetworkManager&lt;/code&gt; to see if I could catch one&#xA;of these events and figure out what was causing the error. And voilá, I found the culprit! The&#xA;error was being triggered by the network manager triggering an event every time a new virtual&#xA;interface was being created. This event was being propagated and picked up by browsers and&#xA;electron applications that were picking up this event as a network change that required a&#xA;reconnection.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I had to know figure out who and why was this virtual interface was being created every minute. I&#xA;inspected my &lt;code&gt;docker events&lt;/code&gt; and the reason was obvious immediately. I was running a few&#xA;containers (mainly Redis) that was running a healthchecks every minute. In order to perform this&#xA;healthcheck, Docker was creating an ephimeral virtual interface that was created and immediately&#xA;destroyed. This is the network event involving my network interfaces that was being picked up by&#xA;the network manager and propagated up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The issue was simple, I disabled all healthcheck on my containers and it solved the problem. It&#xA;may seem obvious now, but it was a pretty hard one to debug.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also tried to blacklist virtual interfaces in the network manager so the changes triggered by&#xA;healthcheck virtual interfaces are not propagated up, but this ended up not working reliably. It may&#xA;be worth exploring this approach further as it seems cleaner (and more nuclear) but the time I&#xA;time-boxed for this debugging was up and I had to move to something else. I guess this is good&#xA;enough for now, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted if this issue (or something related) ends up surfacing in the&#xA;world again, or if I end up finding the time to debug and find a better fix for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Coding in P2P Networks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;adlrocha---network-coding-in-p2p-networks&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adlrocha.substack.com/people/3137214-alfonso-de-la-rocha&#34;&gt;@adlrocha - Network Coding in P2P Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;linear-combinations-on-the-fly&#34;&gt;Linear combinations on-the-fly!&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not going to lie, writing my Sunday publication is getting harder and harder as I go deeper into my research on file-sharing in P2P networks. I spend almost all of my waking hours working on it, and by the end of the day I don&amp;rsquo;t have any more brain power left to start writing one of these pieces. Fortunately, &lt;strong&gt;I am working on such an exciting field that I can always choose one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring throughout the week and just start writing about it.&lt;/strong&gt; And this has been the case for this publication, where I will share my excitement about network coding schemes in P2P networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traversing the NAT</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-nat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;adlrocha---traversing-the-nat&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adlrocha.substack.com/people/3137214-alfonso-de-la-rocha&#34;&gt;@adlrocha - Traversing the NAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-quest-for-direct-global-connectivity-between-devices&#34;&gt;A quest for direct global connectivity between devices.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F60977c6b-a665-41bc-b7f8-c9332f5a3909_1000x562.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F60977c6b-a665-41bc-b7f8-c9332f5a3909_1000x562.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;aerial photography of lake&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty obsessed with the future of the Internet, how it may look like, and the technological path towards it. All this started when I jumped into writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://adlrocha.substack.com/p/adlrocha-my-vision-for-a-new-internet&#34;&gt;my personal vision for a new Internet&lt;/a&gt;. A few weeks later I was invited to participate in a discussion panel about the future of the Internet and web3 in the European Blockchain Convention, and as preparation for the panel &lt;a href=&#34;https://adlrocha.substack.com/p/adlrocha-what-the-next-generation&#34;&gt;I decided to interview a bunch of colleagues in the field to learn their thoughts on the matter&lt;/a&gt;. I concluded this series with last week&amp;rsquo;s discussion on &lt;a href=&#34;https://adlrocha.substack.com/p/adlrocha-what-if-we-had-local-first&#34;&gt;local-first software and the technologies to enable it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
