<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Coding in P2P Networks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Network Coding in P2P Networks Linear combinations on-the-fly! I am not going to lie, writing my Sunday publication is getting harder and harder as I go deeper into my research on file-sharing in P2P networks. I spend almost all of my waking hours working on it, and by the end of the day I don&amp;rsquo;t have any more brain power left to start writing one of these pieces. Fortunately, I am working on such an exciting field that I can always choose one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring throughout the week and just start writing about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traversing the NAT</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-nat/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Traversing the NAT A quest for direct global connectivity between devices. 
These past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty obsessed with the future of the Internet, how it may look like, and the technological path towards it. All this started when I jumped into writing my personal vision for a new Internet. A few weeks later I was invited to participate in a discussion panel about the future of the Internet and web3 in the European Blockchain Convention, and as preparation for the panel I decided to interview a bunch of colleagues in the field to learn their thoughts on the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>