<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tils on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/til/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tils on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ikea-oriented development</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-26-ikea-oriented/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-26-ikea-oriented/</guid>
      <description>Ikea-oriented development Today I want to share an interesting idea that I feel all software engineers will appreciate in some way (either because they strong agree or disagree): Ikea-oriented development.
The TL;DR idea behind this approach to software engineering is:
  Packaging is the product: Delivering data is expensive. Pre-packaged depedencies: If you can’t bundle allen keys for your hex fasteners, stick to screws. Likewise, if you lack the engineering resources to support multiple SDKs, make damn sure your web API is easy enough to access with curl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some AI-related links</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-26-ai-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-26-ai-links/</guid>
      <description>June 2023 AI-related Reading List I just found myself with a few dozens of tabs opened with AI-related resources that I wanted to read. I feel that having them in RAM (i.e. opened in my browser) was starting overwhelm me, as I felt I could never find the time to read them (leading to a really uncomfortable feeling while I had to make progress in my day-to-day job). Hence, I decided to periodically move from RAM to a &amp;ldquo;persistent storage&amp;rdquo; my reading lists so that I could pick them up once I have some time for them (and in the process share them with others that my be interested).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoatCounter: Easy and open-source web analytics</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-14-goatcounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-14-goatcounter/</guid>
      <description>GoatCounter: Easy and open-source web analytics. I was trying to find an analytics system that was open-source, that respected privacy as much as possible, and that was easy to set up. Suprisingly, I was able to find one after the first search without having to navigate several blog posts or Twitter threads with &amp;ldquo;the best analytics tools you should really now about in 2023&amp;rdquo;.
As their website states, GoatCounter &amp;ldquo;is an open source web analytics platform available as a free donation-supported hosted service or self-hosted app.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
