<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</guid>
      <description>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm  Searching new runtimes for AI
 I came up with an (obvious) idea the other day that led to me to the following question: &amp;ldquo;would it be possible to run LLM inference from Wasm?&amp;quot;. Being able to compile ML models into Wasm would allow us to run them in a heterogeneous set of runtimes and devices, including mobile or the browser. However, would running these models in Wasm offer access to the low-level computational resources of the device required for an efficient execution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late arrival to the fuss of LLMs</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</guid>
      <description>Late Arrival to the Fuss of LLMs  From zero to zero-point-one in a few resources
 After spending some time reading about the state of AI at a high-level, it was time to dive into the details. For obvious reasons, I decided LLMs were a good first-stop for my AI enlightenment. What are LLMs and how they work (because apparently the why is still a burning open question)?.
Rivers of digital ink have been spilled lately with gentle introductions and deep illustrations of how LLMs and their underlying transformer architectures work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of the current state of AI</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Making sense of the current state of AI  Or rather, my limited view as an outsider.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stay up to date (at least at a high level) with all the new developments in the field of AI, but with my full-time job it has been quite a challenge. This can be even more of a challenge when your full-time job is not closely related with the field of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Coding in P2P Networks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Network Coding in P2P Networks Linear combinations on-the-fly! I am not going to lie, writing my Sunday publication is getting harder and harder as I go deeper into my research on file-sharing in P2P networks. I spend almost all of my waking hours working on it, and by the end of the day I don&amp;rsquo;t have any more brain power left to start writing one of these pieces. Fortunately, I am working on such an exciting field that I can always choose one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring throughout the week and just start writing about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traversing the NAT</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-nat/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Traversing the NAT A quest for direct global connectivity between devices. 
These past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty obsessed with the future of the Internet, how it may look like, and the technological path towards it. All this started when I jumped into writing my personal vision for a new Internet. A few weeks later I was invited to participate in a discussion panel about the future of the Internet and web3 in the European Blockchain Convention, and as preparation for the panel I decided to interview a bunch of colleagues in the field to learn their thoughts on the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
