<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decentralization on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/decentralization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decentralization on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/decentralization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From open-source to open-platforms</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - From open-source Ato open-platforms Originally published in 2022 in the newsletter
 On the killer app for blockchains
 It&amp;rsquo;s been over 6 months since my last publication. I could start making up dozens of excuses to justify my absence, but honestly? it has just been a matter of priorities. I realized that all of the time I was spending finding topics to write about, researching them, and writing the publication, could be better spent building new systems (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@adlrocha - Why do we need a new Internet?</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Why do we need a decentralized Internet? Today I had what we could call a crisis of faith. After so many years working in the web3 space, and seeing so much speculation and cool tech solving artificial problems, I was wondering &amp;ldquo;do we really need a new Internet? Or is it just another artificial problem we are creating to have an excuse to attract investment and work in cool tech?. So I decided to write down a list of reasons why a company or an individual would choose to deploy their applications or services over a decentralized Internet over our current one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
