<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</guid>
      <description>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm  Searching new runtimes for AI
 I came up with an (obvious) idea the other day that led to me to the following question: &amp;ldquo;would it be possible to run LLM inference from Wasm?&amp;quot;. Being able to compile ML models into Wasm would allow us to run them in a heterogeneous set of runtimes and devices, including mobile or the browser. However, would running these models in Wasm offer access to the low-level computational resources of the device required for an efficient execution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late arrival to the fuss of LLMs</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</guid>
      <description>Late Arrival to the Fuss of LLMs  From zero to zero-point-one in a few resources
 After spending some time reading about the state of AI at a high-level, it was time to dive into the details. For obvious reasons, I decided LLMs were a good first-stop for my AI enlightenment. What are LLMs and how they work (because apparently the why is still a burning open question)?.
Rivers of digital ink have been spilled lately with gentle introductions and deep illustrations of how LLMs and their underlying transformer architectures work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of the current state of AI</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Making sense of the current state of AI  Or rather, my limited view as an outsider.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stay up to date (at least at a high level) with all the new developments in the field of AI, but with my full-time job it has been quite a challenge. This can be even more of a challenge when your full-time job is not closely related with the field of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Resolutions</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-02-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-02-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>@aldrocha - 2024 Resolutions  Getting back into good habits, and entering the world of AI.
 Is great to be back! It feels like ages since I last wrote here. These past few years have been full of intense work, stressing deadlines, and a clear neglect for this newsletter. However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I&amp;rsquo;ve completely stopped writing. Actually, last year has been the year that I&amp;rsquo;ve written the most in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From open-source to open-platforms</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - From open-source Ato open-platforms Originally published in 2022 in the newsletter
 On the killer app for blockchains
 It&amp;rsquo;s been over 6 months since my last publication. I could start making up dozens of excuses to justify my absence, but honestly? it has just been a matter of priorities. I realized that all of the time I was spending finding topics to write about, researching them, and writing the publication, could be better spent building new systems (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@adlrocha - Why do we need a new Internet?</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Why do we need a decentralized Internet? Today I had what we could call a crisis of faith. After so many years working in the web3 space, and seeing so much speculation and cool tech solving artificial problems, I was wondering &amp;ldquo;do we really need a new Internet? Or is it just another artificial problem we are creating to have an excuse to attract investment and work in cool tech?. So I decided to write down a list of reasons why a company or an individual would choose to deploy their applications or services over a decentralized Internet over our current one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never take Marshaling for granted</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-03-marshal-dynamic-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-03-marshal-dynamic-types/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Never take Marshaling for granted Marshaling interfaces in Go.
We sometimes take marshaling for granted, but** there is more than one occasion in which you have no choice but to write your own custom marshaller. Either because your compiler/marshal library is not able to infer how to automatically marshal your objects, because your marshaler is not generating the right output (we saw last weekhow a JSON document can be parsed with different values across microservices, leading to a variety of potential security risk), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Ethereum 2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Demystifying Ethereum 2.0 A gentle introduction to what is yet to come! Ethereum 2.0 is set to launch on the 1st of December, and using this as an excuse I decided to invest some time to learn a bit more about the new developments happening in the Ethereum space.
What is Eth2?  Eth2 refers to a set of interconnected upgrades that will make Ethereum more scalable, more secure, and more sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Social Incentive Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-social-broken-incentive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-social-broken-incentive/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Broken Social Incentive Systems And how short-term thinking can be dangerous 
 &amp;ldquo;If our descendants were to diagnose the ills of 21st-century civilization, they would observe a dangerous short-termism: a collective failure to escape the present moment and look further ahead. The world is saturated in information, and standards of living have never been higher, but so often it&amp;rsquo;s a struggle to see beyond the next news cycle, political term, or business quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Coding in P2P Networks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Network Coding in P2P Networks Linear combinations on-the-fly! I am not going to lie, writing my Sunday publication is getting harder and harder as I go deeper into my research on file-sharing in P2P networks. I spend almost all of my waking hours working on it, and by the end of the day I don&amp;rsquo;t have any more brain power left to start writing one of these pieces. Fortunately, I am working on such an exciting field that I can always choose one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring throughout the week and just start writing about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traversing the NAT</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-nat/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Traversing the NAT A quest for direct global connectivity between devices. 
These past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty obsessed with the future of the Internet, how it may look like, and the technological path towards it. All this started when I jumped into writing my personal vision for a new Internet. A few weeks later I was invited to participate in a discussion panel about the future of the Internet and web3 in the European Blockchain Convention, and as preparation for the panel I decided to interview a bunch of colleagues in the field to learn their thoughts on the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My vision for a new Internet</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - My vision for a new Internet Where everyone can become an ISP | Alfonso de la Rocha

I was skimming through this paper (A Public Option for the Core), when I read the following sentence in the abstract: *&amp;ldquo;In this paper we discuss both the challenges and the opportunities that make this an auspicious time to revisit how we might best structure the Internet&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.&amp;quot; *And I said, well this may be something worth reflecting on and discussing in my newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
