<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web3 on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/web3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web3 on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/web3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RandomX: PoW for general-purpose CPUs</title>
      <link>/til/2023-08-10-randomx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-08-10-randomx/</guid>
      <description>RandomX: PoW for general-purpose CPUs I was discussing today with the Fluence Labs team and they were describing how they want their Fluence network to be run by a PoW consensus algorithm. They want miners to be able to mine new blocks with just a general-purpose CPU, without requiring expensive GPUs or ASICs. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that there was already a PoW implementation, originally implemented for Monero, that is optimized for its use in general purpose CPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Ethereum 2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Demystifying Ethereum 2.0 A gentle introduction to what is yet to come! Ethereum 2.0 is set to launch on the 1st of December, and using this as an excuse I decided to invest some time to learn a bit more about the new developments happening in the Ethereum space.
What is Eth2?  Eth2 refers to a set of interconnected upgrades that will make Ethereum more scalable, more secure, and more sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My vision for a new Internet</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - My vision for a new Internet Where everyone can become an ISP | Alfonso de la Rocha

I was skimming through this paper (A Public Option for the Core), when I read the following sentence in the abstract: *&amp;ldquo;In this paper we discuss both the challenges and the opportunities that make this an auspicious time to revisit how we might best structure the Internet&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.&amp;quot; *And I said, well this may be something worth reflecting on and discussing in my newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
