<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@adlrocha</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-02-18-wasm-llm/</guid>
      <description>Running LLMs and ML in Wasm  Searching new runtimes for AI
 I came up with an (obvious) idea the other day that led to me to the following question: &amp;ldquo;would it be possible to run LLM inference from Wasm?&amp;quot;. Being able to compile ML models into Wasm would allow us to run them in a heterogeneous set of runtimes and devices, including mobile or the browser. However, would running these models in Wasm offer access to the low-level computational resources of the device required for an efficient execution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Hibernate on my Linux laptop (Pop OS)</title>
      <link>/til/2024-02-13-linux-hibernate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2024-02-13-linux-hibernate/</guid>
      <description>Enabling Hibernate on my Linux laptop (Pop OS)  Or how to keep your battery after closing your laptop.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux on my laptop for more than a decade now. It is well-known that depending on the distro and the laptop you use, &amp;ldquo;deep sleep&amp;rdquo; and/or hibernate may not be well-supported. This means that even every time that I closed the lid of my laptop, its battery will end up draining until it runs out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late arrival to the fuss of LLMs</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-18-intro-llms/</guid>
      <description>Late Arrival to the Fuss of LLMs  From zero to zero-point-one in a few resources
 After spending some time reading about the state of AI at a high-level, it was time to dive into the details. For obvious reasons, I decided LLMs were a good first-stop for my AI enlightenment. What are LLMs and how they work (because apparently the why is still a burning open question)?.
Rivers of digital ink have been spilled lately with gentle introductions and deep illustrations of how LLMs and their underlying transformer architectures work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember `to(&#39;cpu&#39;)` in Pytorch to release GPU memory</title>
      <link>/til/2024-01-11-pytorch-collab-to-cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2024-01-11-pytorch-collab-to-cpu/</guid>
      <description>Remember to(&#39;cpu&#39;) in Pytorch to release GPU memory When I saw that Microsoft had released phi-2, a 2.7B parameters LLM, I thought: &amp;ldquo;this is the perfect excuse to get my hands dirty with LLMs&amp;rdquo;. The model was small enough to test it directly inside Google Colab, as it would fit the 15GiB memory GPUs provided in the free plan.
So without further ado, I opened Google Colab, pip installed HF&amp;rsquo;s transformers library, and wrote the following code snippet to test the model:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of the current state of AI</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-10-state-ai/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Making sense of the current state of AI  Or rather, my limited view as an outsider.
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stay up to date (at least at a high level) with all the new developments in the field of AI, but with my full-time job it has been quite a challenge. This can be even more of a challenge when your full-time job is not closely related with the field of AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Resolutions</title>
      <link>/blog/2024-01-02-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024-01-02-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>@aldrocha - 2024 Resolutions  Getting back into good habits, and entering the world of AI.
 Is great to be back! It feels like ages since I last wrote here. These past few years have been full of intense work, stressing deadlines, and a clear neglect for this newsletter. However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I&amp;rsquo;ve completely stopped writing. Actually, last year has been the year that I&amp;rsquo;ve written the most in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From open-source to open-platforms</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-10-open-platforms/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - From open-source Ato open-platforms Originally published in 2022 in the newsletter
 On the killer app for blockchains
 It&amp;rsquo;s been over 6 months since my last publication. I could start making up dozens of excuses to justify my absence, but honestly? it has just been a matter of priorities. I realized that all of the time I was spending finding topics to write about, researching them, and writing the publication, could be better spent building new systems (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When should one use Rust&#39;s `Pin&lt;&gt;`?</title>
      <link>/til/2023-08-29-rust-pin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-08-29-rust-pin/</guid>
      <description>When should one use Rust&amp;rsquo;s Pin&amp;lt;&amp;gt;? The other day I was reviewing some code from the Fendermint project that I am currently contributing to, and I had to ask the author of the PR directly, &amp;ldquo;man! you have to teach me when I am supposed to use Pin&amp;lt;&amp;gt;. I see you are using it all over the place in this API, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know why&amp;rdquo;. His immediate answer was a bit surprising although kind of expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RandomX: PoW for general-purpose CPUs</title>
      <link>/til/2023-08-10-randomx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-08-10-randomx/</guid>
      <description>RandomX: PoW for general-purpose CPUs I was discussing today with the Fluence Labs team and they were describing how they want their Fluence network to be run by a PoW consensus algorithm. They want miners to be able to mine new blocks with just a general-purpose CPU, without requiring expensive GPUs or ASICs. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that there was already a PoW implementation, originally implemented for Monero, that is optimized for its use in general purpose CPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>80,000 hours: Positive impact jobs</title>
      <link>/til/2023-07-21-80000/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-07-21-80000/</guid>
      <description>8,000 hours: Positive impact jobs I am genuinely worried about the existential risk that AI may pose to humanity in the next decade. Some people take this as a unreal threat inherited from science fiction movies, but I beg to differ. I have studied AI fundamentals when I was in college, and I even ended up doing AI professionally a decade ago for a few months (when LLMs weren&amp;rsquo;t a thing, the transformer paper had just been published, and random forest was still winning Kaggle competitions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the size of Solidity contracts</title>
      <link>/til/2023-07-10-solidity-contract-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-07-10-solidity-contract-size/</guid>
      <description>Reducing the size of Solidity contracts I am currently working on a project that we call IPC (InterPlanetary Consensus). We are now implementing the core logic of the protocol in a set of Solidity contracts. Unfortunately, the implementation of one of the contracts of the protocol, the Gateway, was too large to be deployed (over the 24KB limit), so we had to figure out ways to reduce its size. This post, is a great introduction of the different approaches to fight the contract size limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikea-oriented development</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-26-ikea-oriented/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-26-ikea-oriented/</guid>
      <description>Ikea-oriented development Today I want to share an interesting idea that I feel all software engineers will appreciate in some way (either because they strong agree or disagree): Ikea-oriented development.
The TL;DR idea behind this approach to software engineering is:
  Packaging is the product: Delivering data is expensive. Pre-packaged depedencies: If you can’t bundle allen keys for your hex fasteners, stick to screws. Likewise, if you lack the engineering resources to support multiple SDKs, make damn sure your web API is easy enough to access with curl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@adlrocha - Why do we need a new Internet?</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-06-26-decentralized-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Why do we need a decentralized Internet? Today I had what we could call a crisis of faith. After so many years working in the web3 space, and seeing so much speculation and cool tech solving artificial problems, I was wondering &amp;ldquo;do we really need a new Internet? Or is it just another artificial problem we are creating to have an excuse to attract investment and work in cool tech?. So I decided to write down a list of reasons why a company or an individual would choose to deploy their applications or services over a decentralized Internet over our current one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2023 AI-related Reading List</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-26-ai-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-26-ai-links/</guid>
      <description>June 2023 AI-related Reading List I just found myself with a few dozens of tabs opened with AI-related resources that I wanted to read. I feel that having them in RAM (i.e. opened in my browser) was starting overwhelm me, as I felt I could never find the time to read them (leading to a really uncomfortable feeling while I had to make progress in my day-to-day job). Hence, I decided to periodically move from RAM to a &amp;ldquo;persistent storage&amp;rdquo; my reading lists so that I could pick them up once I have some time for them (and in the process share them with others that my be interested).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoatCounter: Easy and open-source web analytics</title>
      <link>/til/2023-06-14-goatcounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/til/2023-06-14-goatcounter/</guid>
      <description>GoatCounter: Easy and open-source web analytics. I was trying to find an analytics system that was open-source, that respected privacy as much as possible, and that was easy to set up. Suprisingly, I was able to find one after the first search without having to navigate several blog posts or Twitter threads with &amp;ldquo;the best analytics tools you should really now about in 2023&amp;rdquo;.
As their website states, GoatCounter &amp;ldquo;is an open source web analytics platform available as a free donation-supported hosted service or self-hosted app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never take Marshaling for granted</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-03-marshal-dynamic-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-03-marshal-dynamic-types/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Never take Marshaling for granted Marshaling interfaces in Go.
We sometimes take marshaling for granted, but** there is more than one occasion in which you have no choice but to write your own custom marshaller. Either because your compiler/marshal library is not able to infer how to automatically marshal your objects, because your marshaler is not generating the right output (we saw last weekhow a JSON document can be parsed with different values across microservices, leading to a variety of potential security risk), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Ethereum 2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-11-demystifying-ethereum2.0/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Demystifying Ethereum 2.0 A gentle introduction to what is yet to come! Ethereum 2.0 is set to launch on the 1st of December, and using this as an excuse I decided to invest some time to learn a bit more about the new developments happening in the Ethereum space.
What is Eth2?  Eth2 refers to a set of interconnected upgrades that will make Ethereum more scalable, more secure, and more sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Social Incentive Systems</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-social-broken-incentive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-social-broken-incentive/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Broken Social Incentive Systems And how short-term thinking can be dangerous 
 &amp;ldquo;If our descendants were to diagnose the ills of 21st-century civilization, they would observe a dangerous short-termism: a collective failure to escape the present moment and look further ahead. The world is saturated in information, and standards of living have never been higher, but so often it&amp;rsquo;s a struggle to see beyond the next news cycle, political term, or business quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Coding in P2P Networks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-network-coding/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Network Coding in P2P Networks Linear combinations on-the-fly! I am not going to lie, writing my Sunday publication is getting harder and harder as I go deeper into my research on file-sharing in P2P networks. I spend almost all of my waking hours working on it, and by the end of the day I don&amp;rsquo;t have any more brain power left to start writing one of these pieces. Fortunately, I am working on such an exciting field that I can always choose one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring throughout the week and just start writing about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traversing the NAT</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-10-nat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-10-nat/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - Traversing the NAT A quest for direct global connectivity between devices. 
These past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty obsessed with the future of the Internet, how it may look like, and the technological path towards it. All this started when I jumped into writing my personal vision for a new Internet. A few weeks later I was invited to participate in a discussion panel about the future of the Internet and web3 in the European Blockchain Convention, and as preparation for the panel I decided to interview a bunch of colleagues in the field to learn their thoughts on the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My vision for a new Internet</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - My vision for a new Internet Where everyone can become an ISP | Alfonso de la Rocha

I was skimming through this paper (A Public Option for the Core), when I read the following sentence in the abstract: *&amp;ldquo;In this paper we discuss both the challenges and the opportunities that make this an auspicious time to revisit how we might best structure the Internet&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.&amp;quot; *And I said, well this may be something worth reflecting on and discussing in my newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Resources</title>
      <link>/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 18:00:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/</guid>
      <description>Learning Resources The Internet is full of useful learning resources, but is generally hard to keep track of all of the useful stuff out there. This page collects a useful list of resources that may come handy in the future for many (especially me).
Cryptography  VDF Research Proof of Space  Rust  RISC-V using Rust  Blockchain  Solidity patterns  Fundamentals  What happens when you type google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patrons</title>
      <link>/patrons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 18:00:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/patrons/</guid>
      <description>Become a sponsor of my work! I have a lot of ideas, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to develop them. Financial independence would give me the ability to develop the ideas and research I share in this site and in my newsletter. If you see my ideas become a reality, become a sponsor of my work. Right now I am only accepting sponsors for my newsletter, but this will change in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
