<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ideas on @adlrocha</title>
    <link>/tags/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ideas on @adlrocha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need a new Internet?</title>
      <link>/blog/2023-06-26-green/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023-06-26-green/</guid>
      <description>Why do we need a decentralized Internet? Today I had what we could call a crisis of faith. After so many years working in the web3 space, and seeing so much speculation and cool tech solving artificial problems, I was wondering &amp;ldquo;do we really need a new Internet? Or is it just another artificial problem we are creating to have an excuse to attract investment and work in cool tech?. So I decided to write down a list of reasons why a company or an individual would choose to deploy their applications or services over a decentralized Internet over our current one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My vision for a new Internet</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:16:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-09-vision-internet/</guid>
      <description>@adlrocha - My vision for a new Internet Where everyone can become an ISP | Alfonso de la Rocha

I was skimming through this paper (A Public Option for the Core), when I read the following sentence in the abstract: *&amp;ldquo;In this paper we discuss both the challenges and the opportunities that make this an auspicious time to revisit how we might best structure the Internet&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.&amp;quot; *And I said, well this may be something worth reflecting on and discussing in my newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
